MENBERE HAILU

Addis Ababa, Ethiopia |+251904731753 |menberehailu35@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/menbere-hailu-6b5761124/

SUMMARY

I am a Google Data analytics certified data analyst, Lecturer and BI Analyst/PowerBI Analyst who wants to specialize on data analyst tasks like data collecting, organizing, and analyzing data sets and providing effective dashboard report helps to make decision to improve the organization products and services especially on sales and digital marketing.

SKILLS

- **Database**: SQL, R, MySQL
- Data Analytics: Data Modeling, Data Queries, Web Scraping, Statistics, Data Pipeline
- Data science: Machine Learning
- **Python**: Python 3, Pandas, Matplotlib, NumPy
- Business Intelligence: Microsoft PowerBI, Tableau
- Data Warehousing: ETL processes, data cleansing, data validation

Experience

26/06/2023-Present: SQL and MicrosoftPowerBI Trainer

Nanolink Data Analytics And consultancy: United states (Remote)

- Providing Database, SQL, MSBI and MicrosoftPowerBI Training to Data Analytics students
- Preparing Academic Curriculum for Data analytics Training

10/5/2022- 1/7/2023: Business Intelligence Analyst (PowerBI Analyst)

Epic Game: United states (Remote)

- ➤ Accomplishment: Spearheaded the development and implementation of a groundbreaking BI solution that significantly enhanced reporting accuracy and efficiency by 25%, positioning the organization for data-driven success.
- > Conducted in-depth analysis of large datasets to identify patterns, trends, and opportunities for process improvement.
- Collaborated with business stakeholders to gather requirements and designed effective data models and dashboards.
- Automated data extraction, transformation, and loading (ETL) processes, reducing manual effort and ensuring data accuracy.

➤ Accomplishment: Presented key findings and strategic recommendations to senior management, influencing decision-making, and contributing to a 15% increase in revenue.

1/1/2021- 1/5/2022: Data analyst/PowerBI Analyst

Dashen Brewery: Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

- Assisted in the development of Power BI reports to support business operations and decision-making.
- > Conducted data cleansing and validation to ensure accuracy and completeness of datasets.
- ➤ Collaborated with IT teams to troubleshoot data-related issues and optimize database performance.
- ➤ Participated in the design and implementation of data visualization solutions for internal and external stakeholders.

2022- Present: Lecturer and Researcher

University of Gondar, Ethiopia

 Teaching and consulting university students and Doing different research and projects in the field of Machine learning, Artificial intelligence and NLP

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

2017 Bachelor of Science (BSC): Information Systems with 3.92 CGPA

University of Gondar, Gondar, Ethiopia

2021 Master of Science (MSc): Information systems with 3.95 CGPA with Very good thesis result University of Gondar, Gondar, Ethiopia.

CERTIFICATE

Fundamental of Digital Marketing and social Media Marketing

https://learndigital.withgoogle.com/digitalgarage/course/digital-marketing

2021 Google analytics for Beginners and Advance

https://analytics.google.com/analytics/academy/profile

2022 Google Data Analytics Professional and Specialization

https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/specialization/certificate/VQ3NJ3CFZR99

2022 SQL for Data Science

https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/records/3X7A4HP9KVJZ

2022 Python Project for Data Science

https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/verify/KEKKLQDU3LUR

2022 Python for Data Science, AI & Development

 $\underline{https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/verify/AMEZDCXLJCP3}$

> I have also one publication on Fake news detection on social media

https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-030-93709-6_31